# Lingyun Yu

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

My research interests span Talking face generation, Articulatory movements-driven 3D Talking Head, Human-Computer Interaction and Video synthesis. The noteworthy research project of mine is to generate realistic talking heads synchronized with the given audio or text input. I am skilled at python and matlab coding, and experienced of Linux system.

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone: +86-13966763354 Email: yuly@mail.ustc.edu.cn

Homepage: http://home.ustc.edu.cn/~yuly WeChat: 13966763354

## **EDUCATION**

09/2015-Present Doctor of Control Science and Engineering

University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

09/2011-06/2015 Bachelor of Electrical Engineering and Automation

China University of Mining and Technology (CUMT)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

#### 10/2017-Present

## Talking Face Generation from Text or Audio input

Independent Completor

- To overcome this problem, we decompose the talking face generation task into two steps: mouth landmarks prediction and video synthesis.
- The time-delayed LSTM is adopted to predict accurate mouth landmarks.
- A network named Face2Vid is proposed to generate video frames conditioned on the predicted
  mouth landmarks. In Face2Vid, the optical flow is employed to model the temporal dependency
  between frames, meanwhile, a self-attention mechanism is introduced to model the spatial
  dependency across image regions.

One Journal paper accepted by ICDM 2019 (Regular paper, 9.08% acceptance rate). One conference paper submitted to IEEE TCSVT.

## 05/2016-09/2017

# Articulatory Synchronicity from Text and Audio Inputs Independent Completor

- We propose a new network architecture for articulatory movement prediction with both text and audio inputs, called BLTRCNN.
- The bottleneck network is adopted to extract the compact bottleneck features as the complementary linguistic features for better performance.
- Combining CNN, LSTM and skip connection can not only acquire local higher-level features but also learn long-range of context information.
- Combining acoustic features and linguistic features as inputs is able to contain more information to boost the performance.

One Journal paper accepted by IEEE TMM

Conference papers accepted by MMM2019 and VCIP2018.

# 09/2017-11/2017

## The personalized co-articulation rule statistics

Independent Completor

- We aim at studying the personalized co-articulation rule among neighboring phonemes by the representation of the mouth shape with both text and audio information as inputs.
- A time-delayed LSTM is used to model the mapping from the linguistic and acoustic features
  to the mouth landmarks.
- By statistical knowledge, we calculate and study the co-articulation rule among neighboring

phonemes.

#### 02/2015-02/2016

# Articulatory movements-driven 3D pronunciation system. Independent Completor

- We proposes an emotional text-driven 3D visual pronunciation system for Mandarin Chinese by generating the emotional articulatory movement trajectory.
- The articulatory movements are predicted by HMM.
- We analyze and summarize the variation of the articulatory movements under different emotions.
   One Journal paper accepted by Multimedia Tools and Applications.
   Conference papers accepted by CCPR2016.

#### 07/2019-04/2019

## The "AI Meets Beauty" Challenge in ACM MM2019 Project Participant

- We propose a novel Generalized-attention Regional Maximal Activation of Convolutions (GR-MAC) descriptor to boosts retrieval performance.
- Attention mechanism is introduced to assign larger weights for target regions.
- Awarded **the 1st place** in the Grand Challenge of AI Meets Beauty.

Conference papers accepted by ACM MM 2019.

## **INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCES**

## 07/2017-01/2019 Iflytek Co.,Ltd

• Given an arbitrary speech clip or text information as input, we aim to generate a talking face video with accurate lip synchronization.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Lingyun Yu et al. Mining Audio, Text and Visual information for Talking face generation IEEE ICDM 2019 (Regular paper, 9.08% acceptance rate)
- Lingyun Yu, Jun Yu, and Qiang Ling. 2018. BLTRCNN Based 3D Articulatory Movement Prediction: Learning Articulatory Synchronicity From Both Text and Audio Inputs. IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (IF:5.452).
- Lingyun Yu et al. Multimodal Inputs Driven Talking Face Generation With Spatial-Temporal Dependency (IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology) (major revision IF: 4.046)
- Lingyun Yu, Yu J, Wang Z. A realistic 3D articulatory animation system for emotional visual pronunciation[J]. Multimedia Tools and Applications, 2017, 76(18): 19241-19262 (IF:2.101).
- Lingyun Yu, Yu J, Ling Q. Deep Neural Network Based 3D Articulatory Movement Prediction Using Both Text and Audio Inputs[C]//International Conference on Multimedia Modeling. Springer, Cham, 2019: 68-79.
- Lingyun Yu, Yu J, Ling Q Synthesizing 3D Acoustic-Articulatory Mapping Trajectories: Predicting Articulatory Movements by Long-Term Recurrent Convolutional Neural Network. IEEE VICP (2018)
- Lingyun Yu, Changwei Luo, and Jun Yu. "An Emotional Text-Driven 3D Visual Pronunciation System for Mandarin Chinese." Chinese Conference on Pattern Recognition. Springer, Singapore, 2016.
- Yu J, **Lingyun Yu**. Synthesizing Photo-Realistic 3D Talking Head: Learning Lip Synchronicity and Emotion from Audio and Video[C]//2018 25th IEEE International Conference on Image Processing. IEEE, 2018: 1448-1452.
- Jun Yu et al., Lingyun Yu, Beauty Pro duct Retrieval Based on Regional Maximum Activation of Convolutions with Generalized Attention. ACM MM 2019 (Accept)
- Yu J, Luo C, Lingyun Yu, et al. Facial video coding/decoding at ultra-low bit-rate: a 2D/3D model-based approach[J]. Multimedia Tools and Applications, 2016: 1-21. (IF: 2.101)
- Luo C, Li R, Lingyun Yu, et al. Automatic Tongue Tracking in X-Ray Images[J]. Chinese Journal of Electronics, 2015, 24(4): 767-771. (IF: 0.945)
- Chuanbin Liu, Hongtao Xie, Zhengjun Zha, Lingyun Yu, Zhineng Chen, and Yongdong Zhang. Bidirectional Attention-Recognition Model for Fine-grained Object Classification. IEEE Transactions on Multimedia.

(Accepted IF: 5.452 SCI II)

## **FUNDS**

National Natural Science Foundation of China (U1736123)

National Natural Science Foundation of China (61572450)

National Natural Science Foundation of China (61303150)

Huawei Innovation Research Program - Flagship Program (ES2100100098)

Iflytek Co.,Ltd. Technology research and development project (ES2100100099)

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

2019/07	1st place.	ACM Multimedia	"AI Meets Beauty"	challenge

2017/09	National Scholarships, USTC	2017/11	Travel Award, 2018 IEEE VCIP
2015/05	Excellent graduates, CUMT	2014/10	Exam-Free Postgraduate to USTC